We played around a little bit with TextView.
我們玩了一會文字顯示。
And the other view we want to learn about now to make our birthday
而另一個我們想學的生日卡顯示
card is the ImageView.
是畫像顯示。
Now here's the XML for ImageView.
現這是畫面顯示的XML。
Let's look at the lines one at a time.
讓我們一行一行看。
The XML element starts with an open angle bracket, ding.
XML原料是一個開括號, 叮。
And then the name of the view [SOUND] and then the list of attributes,
之後是顯示名字[聲音]之後物件的清單,
[SOUND] Piu.
[聲音]。
Then it's followed by a forward slash, and then a closing angle bracket.
之後跟隨前斜槓, 之後關括號。
[SOUND] Boom.
[SOUND] Boom. [聲音]?。
When we wrote the XML for TextView, it displayed text on the screen.
當我們為文字顯示寫XML時, 屏幕顯示文字。
So now, when we write ImageView here, it displays an image on the screen.
所以現在, 當我們在這寫文字顯示, 它於屏幕顯示圖像。
The first attribute is something we haven't seen before.
第一件事物我們之前未曾見過的。
It says android:src equals at drawable/cake.
它說安桌:src等於可劃蛋糕。
This is saying that the source for this image should be found in this file here.
這意思是說這圖像的資源可於這檔案找到。
The file name is called cake.
檔案名字叫蛋糕。
We use the at symbol to say that we're referencing
我們用這符號去說
a resource in the Android app, and drawable is the resource type.
資源是安桌程式, 及可寫是個?資源。
A drawable is like a graphic that will be shown on screen in Android.
一個可劃的就如一個安桌屏幕顯示的表。
And again, cake is the file image name.
而再一次, 蛋糕是檔案的圖像名字。
We don't include the file extension.
我們沒包括名字延伸。
You don't need to say if it's a JPEG or PNG image.
你不用分別這是JPEG或PNG圖。
Just say the file name.
只要說出檔案名字。
If you're wondering where this image came from, well we handle this a little
若你在想這圖像從哪來, 那我你處理這
bit differently in the XML Visualizer compared to the app.
有一點不同於XML觀看比較於程式。
But basically, we loaded in a bunch of images beforehand so
但基本上, 我們一早下載了一堆圖像所以
that you can use them to practice in XML Visualizer.
你可以用來於XML觀看練習。
When you build your app in Android Studio you're going to have to
當你於安桌工作坊建立你的程式你會要
add images manually into your app, into the drawable folder.
手動地於程式上加圖像, 在你的檔案內。
Now, if I try to reference an image that doesn't exist, for
現在, 若我試著找一個不存在的圖像,
example, the toys image does not exist.
例如, 不存在的玩具圖像。
Then there will be an error because toys is not a valid image.
會出現一個錯誤因為玩具並不是一個合適的圖像。
So make sure that you only reference images that are available.
所以緊記只要去找合適的圖像。
So let's change it back by hitting undo.
所以讓我們按取消改回去。
Now we have the width and height, which are set to be wrapped content.
現在我們有闊及高度, 都是設為包容內容。
So that the image view is only as big as the cake image inside of it.
所以圖像顯示只會是蛋糕圖像的大小。
Lastly, we have this attribute called Android:scaledType and
最後, 我們有某事叫Android:scaledType 及
it's set to be center.
它設在中間。
Scale type tells the device how to scale up or
比例類別告訴裝置如何提高或
scale down, based on the bound of the ImageView.
調低比例, 跟句圖像顯示的邊界。
Let's see what that looks like.
讓我們看看這自來如何。
Now you can see the cake image showing up on the device.
現在你可看到蛋糕圖像於裝置上出現。
The cake image is actually pretty large, and it's larger than the screen size.
蛋糕圖像其實很大, 而它大過於屏幕的大小。
So when we say scaleType,
所以當我們說比例種類,
it doesn't change the size of the image, it just centers it.
這不會改變圖像的大小, 只會置於中間。
So we see that the cake image is actually really big,
所以我們看到蛋糕圖像其實很大,
but this is the center of the cake image.
但這是蛋糕圖像的中間。
We can set other values for scaleType, such as centerCrop.
我們可以設其他值給比例類, 如	centerCrop。
This scales down the image to fit the height and width of the view.
這會縮小圖像去合顯示的高及闊。
In this case, we're constrained by the sides of the screen.
在這情況,我們比屏幕的周邊所限制。
We also maintain the aspect ratio of the original image so
我們亦維持原本圖像的比例令此
it doesn't get distorted.
不會扭曲。
Once we scale it down, we also center the image, and
當我們把此縮小,我們亦把圖像置中及
then crop it so that it fits this ViewSize.
剪短它令此配合這圖像大小。
When displaying photographs, I like to use center crop.
當顯示相片,我喜歡用置中剪短。
This is because it's typically okay to crop off the edges of the photograph
這是因為剪短相片的周邊一般都沒問題
in order to achieve this edge to edge look.
為了這邊好看些。
When images go edge to edge without any white border or
當圖像邊並邊而沒有白邊時或
anything, this is what we call a full bleed image.
其他, 這我們叫全圖像類。
We use a lot of full bleed images in the material design guide.
我們於物件設計教導內常用全圖像。
Here are some examples.
這類有一些例子。
You see how the images go edge to edge here, and
你可以看到圖像如何邊並邊, 及
it give it a nice immersive feel.
這給予一個很好的沉浸式感覺。
Okay, now it is time for you to try.
好了, 現在到你試了。
Specifically, we would love for you to be able to change the height and
尤其是, 我會很想你可以改變圖像顯示的高度及
width of the image view to be a fixed dp value.
闊度設為點值。
Try something like 100dp.
試試如100點。
Then change the scale type between center and center crop, and
之後改變比例類於中間或中間剪短之間及
you can also adjust the height and width of the image accordingly.
你亦可以改變圖像的高及闊度。
For example, what happens if you change the height and width of the image view
例如, 若你改變圖像的高或闊
to be greater than the sides of the device, or what happens if you set
大過於裝置的邊會發生什麼事, 或當你設
the height and width to be something smaller than the size of the device?
高或闊小過於裝置的大小會發生什麼事?
&gt;&gt; In those cases you may see different behavior for center and
於這些情況你可以看到有不?態度於中間
center crop &gt;&gt; Also, try to change the image to
或中間短。同時試試改圖像成
something else by checking the Available Images link.
另一些東西去檢查可用圖像連結。
We've included a small version of the cake image,
我們加入小蛋糕的版本,
as well as a larger version, so that you can try the different scale types.
同時大版本,因此你可以試試不同比例類。
We also included an Android icon.
我問亦包括了安桌圖像。
Use the link below to get to the XML Visualizer.
用下方的連結去到XML觀看台。